# Kalvik Jakkala

kjakkala@uncc.edu https://itskalvik.github.io/
https://github.com/itskalvik in https://linkedin.com/in/itskalvik
316-226-4000 Charlotte, North Carolina

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in Bayesian learning and mathematical optimization. Specifically, methods that can reliably express uncertainty, make open-set predictions, and incorporate prior domain knowledge. I am currently researching sensor placement and informative path planning using sparse Gaussian processes.

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### **Bayesian Sensor Placement and Informative Path Planning**

May 2020—May 2023

Researching Bayesian approaches for sensor placement and informative path planning in continuous and discrete domains

## Pose Estimation and Action Recognition with mmWave Radar Devices

May 2019—May 2020

Analyzed and developed deep learning algorithms for pose estimation and action recognition from mmWave radar data

#### User Recognition with WiFi routers and mmWave Radar Devices

May 2019—May 2020

Pioneered deep learning algorithms for gait-based user recognition with WiFi routers and mmWave radars

## Real-time Depth Estimation from Monocular Images

Jan 2017—Dec 2017

Studied, implemented, and deployed deep learning methods for real-time depth estimation from monocular images in autonomous underwater and aerial drones

#### **Autonomous Indoor Environment Mapping Drone (Team)**

Aug 2015—May 2016

Developed path planning and object avoidance algorithms for an indoor environment mapping aerial drone

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] **Kalvik Jakkala** and Srinivas Akella. "Bayesian Sensor Placement for Multi-source Localization of Viruses in Wastewater Networks". Manuscript submitted for publication. 2023. URL: https://kdkalvik.github.io/publications/wastewater.
- [2] **Kalvik Jakkala** and Srinivas Akella. "Efficient Sensor Placement from Regression with Sparse Gaussian Processes in Continuous and Discrete Spaces". Manuscript submitted for publication. 2023. URL: https://kdkalvik.github.io/publications/SGP-SP.
- [3] **Kalvik Jakkala** and Srinivas Akella. "Multi-Robot Informative Path Planning from Regression with Sparse Gaussian Processes". Manuscript submitted for publication. 2023.
- [4] Kalvik Jakkala and Srinivas Akella. "Probabilistic Gas Leak Rate Estimation Using Submodular Function Maximization With Routing Constraints". In: *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters* (2022). URL: https://kdkalvik.github.io/publications/gas-leak-estimation.
- [5] Kalvik Jakkala. "Deep Gaussian Processes: A Survey". In: CoRR abs/2106.12135 (2021). URL: https://kdkalvik.github.io/publications/DGP.
- [6] Prabhu Janakaraj, **Kalvik Jakkala**, Arupjyoti Bhuyan, Zhi Sun, Pu Wang, and Minwoo Lee. "STAR: Simultaneous Tracking and Recognition through Millimeter Waves and Deep Learning". In: *12th IFIP Wireless and Mobile Networking Conference*, WMNC 2019. IEEE, 2019. URL: https://kdkalvik.github.io/publications/STAR.
- [7] **Kalvik Jakkala**, Arupjyoti Bhuyan, Zhi Sun, Pu Wang, and Zhuo Cheng. "Deep CSI Learning for Gait Biometric Sensing and Recognition". In: *CoRR* abs/1902.02300 (2019). URL: https://kdkalvik.github.io/publications/CSI.
- [8] Akarsh Pokkunuru, **Kalvik Jakkala**, Arupjyoti Bhuyan, Pu Wang, and Zhi Sun. "NeuralWave: Gait-Based User Identification Through Commodity WiFi and Deep Learning". In: *44th Annual Conference of the Industrial Electronics Society, IECON 2018*. IEEE, 2018. URL: https://kdkalvik.github.io/publications/Neuralwave.

# SKILLS

Research Methods: Gaussian Processes, State-Space Models, Probabilistic Models, Variational Inference, Graph Neural

Networks (GNNs), Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs), Transformers, Generative Flow Networks (GFlowNets-RL), Energy-Based Models, Flow-Based Models,

Diffusion Models, Contrastive Representation Learning, Metric Learning

Libraries: Tensorflow, PyTorch, OpenCV, Robot Operating System (ROS), SciPy, Pandas, Pyro, GPFlow, Numpy

Languages: Python, C/C++, Matlab, Bash Scripting, SQL

Platforms: Linux, Unix, OpenStack, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Slurm

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# Teaching Assistant (University of North Carolina at Charlotte)

Jan 2021—May 2022

Taught and mentored graduate students in the following courses

- Machine Learning (ITCS8156)
- Algorithms & Data Structures (ITCS8114)

#### **B.S. Teaching Fellow** (Wichita State University)

Aug 2016—May 2018

Co-instructed, graded and tutored undergraduate students in the following programming classes

- Object-oriented programming (CS311)
- Data structures (CS300)
- Introductory C++ programming (CS211)

## **EDUCATION**

# University of North Carolina at Charlotte (PhD)

Aug 2018—Dec 2023

- Computer Science, Machine Learning

## University of North Carolina at Charlotte (MSc)

Aug 2018-May 2021

- Computer Science, concentration in AI, Robotics, and Gaming
- Cumulative GPA: 4.00

## Wichita State University (BSc)

Aug 2014—May 2018

- Computer Science, minor in Mathematics
- Cumulative GPA: 3.45

# ACTIVITIES/AWARDS

# **UNC Charlotte GSSF Grant Recipient**

May 2022

- Awarded the UNC Charlotte Graduate School's Summer Fellowship (GSSF) grant

#### Deans Honor Roll

May 2018, May 2017, Dec 2016, Dec 2014

- Recognized for outstanding academic performance by the Deans office

## Vice President, Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)

Aug 2015—Dec 2016

- Managed the local chapter of ACM and organized educational events on campus

## Vice President, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineering (IEEE)

Aug 2015-Dec 2016

- Managed the local chapter of IEEE and organized educational events on campus